In this video I'm going to give a very brief introduction to Intermediate Code
在这段视频中，我将非常简要地介绍中间代码
and its use in compilers. So the first question to address is, what is
以及它在编译器中的使用。所以第一个要解决的问题是，什么是
Intermediate Code or an Intermediate Language? And as the name suggests, an
中间代码还是中间语言？顾名思义，一个
Intermediate Language is just that, it's a language that's intermediate between the
中间语言就是这样，它是介于两种语言之间的一种语言
source language and the target language. So, keep in mind what a compiler does. So
源语言和目标语言。因此，请记住编译器的作用。所以
a compiler takes a program written in some source language. And, it provides a
编译器接受用某种源语言编写的程序。而且，它还提供了一个
translation of that program into some target language And so in this class, for
将程序翻译成某种目标语言，因此在这个类中，
example, where often our source language is cool and our target language is mixed
例如，我们的源语言通常很酷，而我们的目标语言是混合的
assembly code. Now, an Intermediate Language actually lives in between these
汇编代码。现在，一种中间语言实际上存在于这两种语言之间
two and a compiler that uses an Intermediate Language will first translate
两个和使用中间语言的编译器将首先翻译
its source language into the Intermediate Language and then later translate the
将其源语言转换为中间语言，然后再将
intermediate the code in the Intermediate Language into the target language. And you
将中间语言的代码转换为目标语言。而你
might wonder, well why make life so difficult? Why when, why do something in
你可能会想，为什么要让生活变得如此艰难呢？为什么什么时候，为什么要在
two steps if you can do in one step? And it turns out that for many purposes this
如果你能在一步内完成两步的话？事实证明，出于很多目的，这个
intermediate level here is actually quite useful precisely because it provides an
这里的中间级别实际上非常有用，因为它提供了一个
intermediate level of abstraction. So, in particular, the intermediate level may
中间抽象级别。因此，具体地说，中间级别可以
have more details in it than the source language. So for example, if we want to
比源语言有更多的细节。例如，如果我们想要
optimize register usage you know, a source language like Cool has no notion of
优化寄存器使用您知道，像Cool这样的源语言没有
registers at the source level, and so there's no way to even express the kinds
寄存器在源代码级别，因此甚至无法表示类型
of optimizations you might want to do with registers. So an Intermediate Language
您可能想要对寄存器进行的优化。所以一种中间语言
that exposes that at that amount of detail, at least have registers in it will
这表明，在如此详细的情况下，至少在其中有寄存器将
allow you to talk about and, and write algorithms that could try to improve the
允许您讨论和，并编写算法来尝试改进
use of registers in the program. On the other hand, the Intermediate Language
程序中寄存器的使用。另一方面，中间语言
which will also have fewer details than the target. And so it might be for
它的细节也会比目标的少。所以可能是因为
example, if the Intermediate Language is a little bit above the level of the parti
例如，如果中间语言略高于部件级别
cular instruction set of a particular machine, and therefore it's easier to
特定机器的循环指令集，因此更容易
retarget that, that intermediate level of code to lots of different kinds of
将中间代码级别重定目标为许多不同类型
machines. Precisely because doesn't have all the grubby details in a, of a
机器。正是因为没有把所有肮脏的细节都放在一个，一个
particular machine. And, experience has shown, that this is actually a pretty good
特别的机器。而且，经验表明，这实际上是一个相当好的
idea to have Intermediate Language. And, almost all compilers have an Intermediate
拥有中级语言的想法。而且，几乎所有的编译器都有一个中间
Language. I, In fact, in their implementation and some compilers have
语言。事实上，我在它们的实现中和一些编译器已经
more than one. Some compilers actually translate through an entire the series of
不止一个。一些编译器实际上将整个系列的
Intermediate Languages between the source and target language. Now we're only going
源语言和目标语言之间的中间语言。现在我们只去
to consider one Intermediate Language for the rest of this course. The kind of
考虑使用一种中级语言作为本课程的“睡觉”。就是那种
Intermediate Language which we're going to look at is going to be a high level
我们将要看到的中级语言将是一个高级语言
assembly. And so, as I suggested on the previous slide, this language is going to
集合。因此，正如我在上一张幻灯片中所建议的，这种语言将
use register names but it will have an unlimited number, so we can use any number
使用寄存器名称，但它的数量不受限制，因此我们可以使用任何数字
of registers that we like. We're not bound to 32 or 64 registers. The control
我们喜欢的寄存器。我们不受32或64个寄存器的限制。该控件
structures will look a lot like assembly language. In particular, there will be
结构看起来很像汇编语言。特别是，将会有
explicit jumps and labels on instructions. And the language will also have op codes
指令上的显式跳转和标签。并且该语言还将具有操作码
in it so it'll look like assembly language level op codes. But some of these op codes
这样看起来就像汇编语言级别的操作码。但是这些操作码中的一些
will be higher level. So for example, we might have an op code called Push. And
会有更高的水平。例如，我们可能有一个名为PUSH的操作码。和
Push would end up translating into several concrete assembly language instructions
Push最终会翻译成几条具体的汇编语言指令
for a particular target machine. In the intermediate code that we'll be looking
用于特定的目标计算机。在我们将要查看的中间代码中
at, every instruction will have one of two forms. It will either be a binary
在，每个指令将有两种形式中的一种。它将是一个二进制
operation, or it will be a unary operation. And always the arguments on the
操作，否则将是一元操作。而且总是关于
right hand side, in this case the y and the z, will be either registers or
右侧(在本例中为y和z)将是寄存器或
constants. They could also be immediate values. And this is a very, very common
常量。它们也可能是直接的价值。这是一种非常非常普遍的
form of Intermediate Code, so widely used, and so widely used it actually has a name.
中间代码的形式，如此广泛的使用，如此广泛的使用，它实际上是有一个名字的。
It's called Three Address Code because every instruction has at most three
它被称为三个地址码，因为每条指令最多有三个
addresses in it. Two arguments, at most two arguments and then a destination. Now,
地址在里面。两个参数，最多两个参数，然后是目的地。现在,
to see that this code is actually low level notice that you know, higher level
要看到这段代码实际上是低级别的，请注意，更高级别
expressions that involve multiple operations will have to be translated into
涉及多个操作的表达式必须转换为
a sequence of instructions that do only one operation at a time. So, for example,
一次只执行一个操作的指令序列。所以，举个例子，
if I have the expression, x = sorry, x + y z, and let me put in parens here to show
如果我有这样的表达式，x=抱歉，x+yz，让我在这里加上括号来表示
the association. So the times binds more tightly than the plus, we're going to have
协会。所以时间比正数更紧密地联系在一起，我们将会有
to, this can't be written directly in an intermediate , language of this form.
所以，这不能直接用这种形式的中级语言来写。
Instead, we would have to write it something like the following. We have to
取而代之的是，我们必须将其写成如下所示。我们必须得
first compute y z and assign that to a new register or a temporary or you know, a
首先计算y z，并将其分配给新寄存器或临时寄存器，或者您知道的，a
new register t1 to hold the intermediate value. And then we would have to use t1 to
保存中间值的新寄存器T1。然后我们必须使用T1来
compute x + t1, which of course is the value of the entire expression and that
计算x+t1，这当然是整个表达式的值，
would end up getting stored in another register. I noticed that one effect of
最终会被存储在另一个寄存器中。我注意到一个效果是
forcing you to use only one operation at a time. You see, you do one primitive
迫使您一次只能使用一个操作。你看，你做一个原始的
operation at time and then the result of that has to be restored in a register. One
操作，然后其结果必须在寄存器中恢复。一
effect of that is to give every subexpression of the program a name. So,
这样做的效果是给程序的每个子表达式一个名称。所以,
if I look back at this expression here, I see you know, like y z is anonymous.
如果我回过头来看这个表达式，你知道，就像yz是匿名的。
That in this expression x + y 'lt;i>z the expression y 'lt;/i> z itself doesn't have a
在这个表达式x+y‘lt；i>z中，表达式y’lt；/i>z本身没有
name. And by rewriting it like this, I actually name that intermediate result. So
名字。通过这样重写，我实际上给中间结果命名了。所以
again just to summarize this point, one consequence of having to write out
再次总结一下这一点，不得不写下
compound expressions as a sequence of instructions that do a single operation in
复合表达式作为一系列指令，在
time is that every intermediate value will be given its own name. Generating
时间是，每个中间值都将被赋予自己的名称。正在生成
Intermediate Code is very similar to generating assembly code and we're not
中间代码非常类似于生成汇编代码，而我们不是
going to go into this in any detail because it is so similar. But I will
我将详细介绍这一点，因为它们是如此相似。但我会的
sketch it for you, you know, briefly. The main difference between generating
给你画个草图，你知道的，很简短。生成和生成之间的主要区别是
assembly code and generating intermediate code is that we can use any number of
汇编代码和生成中间代码是我们可以使用任意数量的
registers in the Intermediate Language to hold intermediate results. To generate
中间语言中的寄存器以保存中间结果。生成
intermediate code, we could write a function called IGEN for Intermediate Code
中间代码，我们可以为中间代码编写一个名为iGen的函数
Generation that takes two arguments. It takes the expression for which we're
接受两个参数的世代。它采用了我们要表达的表达式
generating code and it takes the register into which the results of that expression
生成代码，并将该表达式的结果放入其中的寄存器
should be stored. And to give you just one example, and this is the only example that
应该储存起来。我只给你们举一个例子，这是唯一一个
I'll do. Let's take a look at generating intermediate code for a+ expressions. I
我会做的。让我们看看如何为+表达式生成中间代码。我
wanna generate code for e1 + e2 and I want the results of that to be stored in the
我想为e1+e2生成代码，并且希望结果存储在
register t, okay? So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to generate code
登记一下，好吗？所以我要做的第一件事就是生成代码
for the subexpressions and I need some place to store the results of the sub
对于子表达式，我需要一些地方来存储子表达式的结果
expressions so I'm just going to make up new register names for those results. So
表达式，所以我要为这些结果编造新的寄存器名称。所以
I'll generate code for e1 and store that in some register, t1 and I'll generate
我将为E1生成代码，并将其存储在某个寄存器T1中，然后我将生成
code for e2 and I'll store the results of that in some register t2. And then, we can
e2的代码，我会将结果存储在某个寄存器t2中。然后，我们就可以
just compute the sum. So t = t1 + t2 and notice that this is a Three Address
只要计算一下和就行了。所以t=t1+t2，请注意这是一个三个地址
Instruction. So we're sticking to the rules here and only using three Address
指示。所以我们坚持这里的规则，只用了三个地址
Instructions In our Intermediate Code Generator. And also notice that because we
我们的中间代码生成器中的说明。还要注意的是，因为我们
have an unlimited number of registers, this actually leads to very simple code
有无限数量的寄存器，这实际上导致了非常简单的代码
generation of intermediate code. In fact, it's even a little bit simpler than
中间代码的生成。事实上，它甚至比
generating code for a stack machine. Recall that, in a stack machine, we had to
为堆叠机生成代码。回想一下，在堆叠机中，我们必须
save the intermediate results here of e1 on the stack. And that involved, you know,
将E1的中间结果保存在堆栈上。这涉及到，你知道，
more than one instruction to actually push the result and adjust the stack pointer
实际推送结果并调整堆栈指针的多条指令
and things like that. And here we can just save it in a register, and, and then just
诸如此类的事情。在这里，我们可以把它保存在一个寄存器里，然后，然后
use that register name later on. So, that is actually all I have to say about
稍后使用该寄存器名称。所以，这就是我要说的全部
Intermediate Code for this course. You should be able to use Intermediate Code at
本课程的中间代码。您应该能够在以下位置使用中间代码
the level in which we are going to be using it in, in lectures. The, in the
我们将在讲座中使用它的水平。那个，在
future videos we'll actually be looking at Intermediate Code quite a bit and using it
在接下来的视频中，我们实际上会更多地了解中间代码并使用它
especially to express certain kinds of optimizations. You should also be able to
特别是表达某种优化。您还应该能够
write simple Intermediate Code programs and you should be able to write algorithms
编写简单的中间代码程序，您应该能够编写算法
that work on Intermediate Code. But I'm not going to expect you to know how to
从事中间代码方面的工作。但我不会指望你知道怎么
generate Intermediate Code because we're not going to discuss it any further. And
生成中间代码，因为我们不会进一步讨论它。和
quite frankly, it doesn't introduce any new any idea. That's really just a
坦率地说，它没有引入任何新的想法。那真的只是一个
variation on the cogeneration ideas that we've already discussed in quite a bit of detail.
我们已经详细讨论过的热电联产想法的变体。